

JUNIOR FRONTEND DEVELOPER

scttjssy@gmail.com

o Philadelphia, PA, 19111, United States

Professional Summary

An enthusiastic and highly motivated quality engineer with 10+ years of experience working in different sectors, looking to transition into the tech industry with a key interest in front end software development. Using my proficiency in HTML, CSS & JavaScript, crafting visually stunning and seamlessly functional front-end wonders, meticulously translating UI/UX blueprints into immersive web and mobile experiences. As a team player, I'm keen to learn and eager to contribute to ensure project success.

Technical Proficiencies

HTML | CSS | JavaScript | MS Word | MS Excel | MS PowerPoint | Outlook

Links

marcusprater.com

Education & Certifications

High School Diploma / Business, Academy at Palumbo, Philadelphia September 2009 — June 2013

Certified Quality Management System Lead Auditor, SAE International

November 2022 — Present

Certificate Number - C17167

(Available upon request)

Core Qualifications

Aesthetic Design | Data Visualization and Presentation | Data Management and Cleansing | Process Improvement and Optimization | Project Management | Analytical and Problem-Solving skills | Excellent Communication and Collaboration skills | Office Administration and Management | Customer Service | Time Management and Organization Skills | Attention to Detail and Accuracy

Employment History

Quality Engineer, WESCORP White Engineering Surfaces Corporation, Newtown, PA

August 2022 — Present

- · Ensure high-quality standards by implementing and overseeing quality assurance measures for special services of airplane components such as wheels, brakes, and landing systems, conforming to customer specifications and Aerospace standards.
- · Expertly conduct metallurgical lab testing, working closely with lab technicians to test coating materials of metals for quality control in adherence with customer and Aerospace specifications.
- Classify all non-conforming parts and materials utilized for coating, abrasive blasting, buffing, and other special services for custom parts with utmost accountability.
- · Lead and supervise the entire internal document review board to ensure compliance with AS9100 and other relevant industry standards for all documents.

- Manage customer specifications and industry standards, expertly revising them whenever new revisions were uploaded by the customer, the vendor, or the industry.
- Demonstrate expert validation and traceability skills, ensuring that all measuring instruments were validated and traceable.

Administrative Assistant, Esstech, Inc., Essington

December 2018 — August 2022

- Proactively communicated with customers through multiple channels, including email, telephone, mail, and FAX, to ensure timely and effective resolution of inquiries and concerns.
- Streamlined order management by revising and entering orders into the system promptly, ensuring accurate tracking and delivery of products to customers.
- Provided exceptional customer service by addressing service-related inquiries and concerns promptly, and escalating calls when necessary.
- Ensured efficient shipping operations by creating daily product description labels, shipping labels, Bills of Lading, and shipment schedules for large customer shipments.
- Ensured compliance with international and domestic shipping regulations by preparing dangerous goods declarations (DGD) for hazardous materials shipments.
- Optimized office operations by handling telephone messages and managing office supplies ordering.
- Increased sales department productivity by promptly identifying and qualifying customer requirements and providing suitable solutions.

Customer Service Representative, Vista Energy, Philadelphia

June 2018 — September 2018

- Fostered and maintained strong relationships with clients, consistently seeking feedback and identifying opportunities for repeat sales
- Provided exceptional service by efficiently and effectively fulfilling customer requests and processing returns to meet their needs
- Demonstrated strong multitasking skills, effectively managing multiple responsibilities simultaneously to ensure timely customer fulfillment.

E-Commerce Specialist, JAKO Enterprises, Philadelphia

February 2017 — June 2018

- Implemented efficient inventory management processes, performed physical counts, and accurately entered data at the sneaker counter to maintain optimal stock levels and prevent stock-outs.
- Demonstrated strong office administration skills, meticulously entering confidential customer information in a fast-paced environment to ensure data accuracy and compliance with data privacy regulations.
- Provided excellent customer service by responding to inquiries and resolving issues through both telephone and computer communication, ensuring customer satisfaction and loyalty.
- Expertly handled and organized sensitive materials in a warehouse environment, using scanning equipment to maintain inventory accuracy and prevent loss or damage.
- Oversaw store merchandise delegation and led a team through a quarterly reevaluation of store requirements for assigned district store, resulting in increased efficiency and profitability.

Customer Service Associate, Kicks USA, Philadelphia

July 2012 — February 2017

 Analyze and interpret daily, weekly, and monthly sales reports to establish and adjust sales targets and objectives for the team

- Manage and reconcile cash flow and receipts for daily retail transactions, ensuring accuracy and completeness of financial records.
- Exceeded sales department objectives and targets by developing and executing effective sales strategies and consistently achieving or surpassing sales quotas.